<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: security | theory.pm]]></title>
  <link href="http://theory.pm/categories/security/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://theory.pm/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-29T11:53:56-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://theory.pm/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David E. Wheeler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Do We Have Right to Security? →]]></title>
<link href="https://securosis.com/blog/do-we-have-a-right-to-security"/>
<updated>2016-02-19T15:26:00-08:00</updated>
<id>http://theory.pm/security/2016/02/19/right-to-security</id>

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Rich Mogull:</p>

<blockquote><p>Don’t be distracted by the technical details. The model of phone, the method
of encryption, the detailed description of the specific attack technique,
and even the feasibility are all irrelevant.</p>

<p>Don’t be distracted by the legal wrangling. By the timing, the courts, or
the laws in question. Nor by politicians, proposed legislation, Snowden, or
speeches at think tanks or universities.</p>

<p>Don’t be distracted by who is involved. Apple, the FBI, dead terrorists, or
common drug dealers.</p>

<p>Everything, all of it, boils down to a single question.</p>

<p><em>Do we have a right to security?</em></p></blockquote>

<p>How about we introduce a bill guaranteeing a right to security. <a href="https://twitter.com/theory/status/700823603122540544">Senator Wyden</a>?</p>

<p>(<a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2016/02/19/right-to-security">Via DF</a>)</p>

<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://theory.pm/security/2016/02/19/right-to-security/">§</a></p>

]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Anthem Breach Harms Consumers →]]></title>
<link href="https://digitalguardian.com/blog/judge-anthem-case-rules-breach-harmed-patients"/>
<updated>2016-02-19T13:56:00-08:00</updated>
<id>http://theory.pm/security/2016/02/19/anthem-breach</id>

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Paul Roberts in Digital Guardian:</p>

<blockquote><p>Whether or not harm has occurred to plaintiffs is critical for courts to
decide whether the plaintiff has a right – or “standing” – to sue in the
first place. But proving that data exposed in a breach has actually been
used for fraud is notoriously difficult.</p>

<p>In her decision in the Anthem case, [U.S. District Judge Lucy] Koh reasoned
that the theft of personal identification information is harm to consumers
in itself, regardless of whether any subsequent misuse of it can be proven.
Allegations of a “concrete and imminent threat of future harm" are enough
to establish an injury and standing in the early stages of a breach suit,
she said.</p></blockquote>

<p>Seems like a no-brainer to me. Personal information is just that: <em>personal.</em>
Organizations that collect and store personal information must take every
step they can to protect it. Failure to do so harms their users, exposing
them to increased risk of identity theft, fraud, surveillance, and abuse. It&rsquo;s
reasonable to expect that firms not be insulated from litigation for failing
to protect user data.</p>

<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://theory.pm/security/2016/02/19/anthem-breach/">§</a></p>

]]></content>
    </entry>
  
</feed>

